<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on rullzers blog</title>
    <link>https://rullzer.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on rullzers blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2015 Roeland Jago Douma -  This work is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rullzer.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure and Easy 2FA in Nextcloud</title>
      <link>https://rullzer.com/2019/04/01/secure-and-easy-2fa-in-nextcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rullzer.com/2019/04/01/secure-and-easy-2fa-in-nextcloud/</guid>
      <description>At Nextcloud we are focused on security and usability. Often these two things conflict. In the last few months we have been working hard to make sure that two-factor authentication is easy to setup and easy to use for all users!
Without much further delay. I&amp;rsquo;m proud to introduce the next step in two-factor authentication the It is really me - Provider.
 Note: the app is still under heavy development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-Factor via Nextcloud Notifications</title>
      <link>https://rullzer.com/2018/10/19/two-factor-via-nextcloud-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rullzer.com/2018/10/19/two-factor-via-nextcloud-notifications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce a new two-factor provider for your Nextcloud: the Notifications Provider. This provider utilizes your existing logged in devices to grant new devices access to your Nextcloud.
 Note: the app is still under heavy development. Still we appreciate testing and feedback!
 The flow is simple. You enable the provider in your personal security settings. Then the next time you log in you can chose to authenticate using a device that is already logged in to your account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a stricter Content Security Policy</title>
      <link>https://rullzer.com/2018/10/18/towards-a-stricter-content-security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rullzer.com/2018/10/18/towards-a-stricter-content-security-policy/</guid>
      <description>A Content Security Policy (CSP) can be used to protect against Cross Site Scripting (XSS) attacks. This is done by having the server tell the browser what resources (executable script, images, etc) can be loaded from where. All this is told to the browser via a header, so if the actual page tries to do something it is not allowed the browser will block it.
At Nextcloud we have deployed a CSP for a while now that limited the resources to be loaded mainly to the domain your Nextcloud is running on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>